We need to remember that agents
eventually still remain just interfaces
to the LLMs. So, every time there's a
request to the LLM and the question is,
what is the data, right? So, all of
these different means of context
engineering, they're just about giving
the right path to choosing the right
words to include in the message. And you
can easily put too many things into the
context window that the actual
instruction gets lost. There are rules
which you kind of shove it into the
context window whether you like it or
not, right? You would put it into that
Claude MD or into use rule in cursor.
Those are mandated, but they take up
context window space. And then you've
got skills.
>> [music]
>> Skills include like cursor rules,
basically a tiny rule, like a little bit
of data that goes into the context
window for the agents to choose to
invoke a skill implicitly. You can
choose to call a skill actively like a
command, in which case you don't need
those things there, but you can also
you expect the agent to invoke the skill
at the relevant time. So, you have to
put a little bit of that red breadcrumb
in the window. There's some development
right now, but maybe separating that out
within the agents. Does it go and
consult some directory? For now, that's
the reality. And then you've got docs.
Docs are just available information for
the agent to find, but they're not
naturally findable for the agent. And
so, you need to either leave a
breadcrumb somewhere like with a rule,
or you just need to name them in a way
that allows for you know, grabs and sort
of other agentic search to find them.
But they purely loaded on demand and
they don't have any price to pay. So,
you can have as many docs as you want.
If you have a thousand skills loaded,
you might really your agents
today. But if you have a thousand docs,
they're just available. It's more about
which docs that it loaded at the right
time and can it actually find them. And
it's a good time to remember as well
that while it's a standard format, they
are not standard models. And so, the
same instruction in the skill text right
now would be loaded by different agents,
by different models. Uh, although we
know in for a fact, we have like
repeating data to show that the same
words would not trigger, you know, haiku
and sonnet and Opus to the same action.
You know, Opus is much more of a kind of
smart-ass, right? And sort of can can
choose to say, "No, I know better and
won't do it." And haiku might sort of
need more sort of detailed instructions.
And so, at the moment, skills don't
really solve for that. They are one
standard unit of context, but it's not
sure that the same words will affect
uh will be the optimal ones for
different agents. So, so I'd sort of
say, you know, think of skills as an
amazing new capability. It is absolutely
worth leaning into. We're doing that in
Tessell. We think they're amazing. They
are maybe the most sort of standard way
right now to reuse context, but like
MCP, I think they're also a piece of the
puzzle. Uh, there will be all sorts of
of sort of tools or just sort of helpers
that we would want to reuse for making
agents successful.
>> That's really interesting. So, so
essentially the standard allows it
provides a kind of standard bolt fitting
in the sense that you can integrate it
with the agents, but your mileage may
vary depending on which agent you use
because it will use it'll it'll assess
the wording and it'll it'll use them
differently depending on how of course
they are implemented in the background.
So, that's that's a that's a good
insight as well.
Okay, so skills. Uh,
we can use them as indie developers, as
hobbyists, as open source developers. We
can also use it as in an organization uh
to describe how we want to do certain
things in in our certain methodologies
and our certain processes that are key
to our organizational uh requirements.
Now, when we think about adding skills
as a first-class citizen into our into
our organizational process, our
development process, um what do we need
to consider when building, owning those
skills, and actually distributing it and
expecting other, you know, professional
developers in our organization to to to
make the best use of that. What do we
need to consider?
>> Yeah, so I think it's a good question
and I think kind of a lure of of skills
is that they they have this immediate
impact on it. You create some static
markdown file, you do it with a create
skill, very very low latency,
and it helps like right now you
immediately can anecdotally see that it
works. But I think just like with
software there are differences between
kind of a one-time it worked and
therefore it's awesome
and something that is a sort of
long-lived assets that you now need to
live with. These are competencies that
you want to reuse across the team. So I
think to to kind of take skills to a
professional level, to a team level, to
an organization level,
you're you're better served by thinking
of skills not as a markdown file, but as
a unit of software. This is a a
competency, a reusable competency that
you want the agents to have.
So this this sort of puts a a different
lens on on what are the tools that you
need to be able to own skills, right?
And to to be able to operate them and
collaborate them on them over time.
There are probably many things to
handle, but I'd say the three to focus
on is one, you need to be able to test
skills just like software, you know, you
if you wanted to remain working or even
just sort of assess whether it works
today, you have to think about what's
correct and then test or in the world of
AI evaluate against those. Two is really
thinking about how do you distribute
that software. We can talk about this
more, but at the moment there's a
kind of easy but you know, sad reality
that people are copying skills all over.
They're designed to be reusable and yet
we kind of copy and duplicate and then
copy everywhere. We've seen that movie,
we know where that ends, so that's not
awesome. And then the third is you have
to think about how do you own them
long-term, you know, they will fall out
of date just like any docs or anything
like that. They the models will change
and so you know, a new model will come
along, it will think it's very
smart, right? Or you would want to use
it with some sort of cheap model or open
model.
And so uh, we have to we have to think
about how do we how do we maintain those
skills? How do we keep them up-to-date?
How do we, uh, allow a team to
collaborate when the person that wrote
them leaves the organization? And so,
it's kind of a whole life cycle
management of it. I think those are the
core ones to think of.